Manish Kumar

Ward Number #7, VPO Talwar, Tehsil Jaisinghpur, District Kangra, Himachal Pradesh, (+91) 8091 894 479 mj.scintilla@outlook.com



About me

Passionate in mobile/software development with 13+ years' experience in the tech industry. Experience in handling development responsibilities from end to end including testing and release of the applications to different app stores like Google Play, App Store and Windows Store.

Skills

Core Languages/Skills:

C++, JAVA, Android, Object Oriented programming, Data Structure and Algorithms

Gaming Frameworks:

cocos2d-x 2d game engine

Public Cloud

AWS, Google Cloud, Azure Cloud

Databases:

DynamoDB, MongoDB and MySQL

Backend Servers:

Parse Platform

Version management:

Git, GitHub

Experience

Fitnessmana - Sr. Software Developer, Location - Panchkula, India

DECEMBER 2021 - AUGUST 2022 (9 months)

- Coordinate with development, testing and deployment teams.
- To hold and participate in product design and code review meetings.
- To participate in product design and code review meetings.
- Ensure smooth functioning of the application.
- Work collaboratively on modules and features development.
- Willingness to learn new technologies, be it commercial or open-source.
- Work collaboratively in a team environment and as an individual
- Testing of the features and release to the play store.

• Majorly involved in android frontend development.

Greysprings - Sr. Software Developer, Location – *Hyderabad/Noida, India*

JULY 2009- NOVEMBER 2021 (12 years and 5 months)

- Coordinate with development, testing and deployment teams.
- To hold and participate in product design and code review meetings.
- To participate in product design and code review meetings.
- Basic scripting and automation knowledge (python).
- Continuously review the product and code for bugs, optimizations and performance improvements.
- Work collaboratively in a team environment and as an individual.
- Participate in sprint planning daily standup and sprint review.
- Willingness to learn new technologies, be it commercial or open-source.
- Worked on various technologies including server management for one of our (now closed down) product.

Education

JULY 2005- JUNE 2008

Jiwaji University, Location - Gwalior, India

Post graduate degree, Master of Computer Applications from School of Studies in Computer
Science and Application

Thakur Jagdev Memorial Degree College, Location - Sujanpur Tihra, HP, India

- Bachelor of Science in Non-Medical stream

Projects

1. Kids Preschool Learning Games

Organization: Greysprings; **Platform:** Android/iOS/Windows platform

Link: https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.greysprings.games

Roles and Responsibilities:

- Participate in sprint planning daily standup and sprint review
- Willingness to learn new technologies mostly open-source.
- Finding and integration best ad network for revenue purposes.
- Time to time framework upgrades to make it work on all supported platforms.
- Features development and handling iOS platform specific modules like in-app purchases, ad framework integration and release.

Tech stack used:

- cocos2d-x game engine, C++, cross platform development

- Specific Android, Windows and iOS platform projects for native support and development of platform specific features like in-app purchases and ads integration.
- Cross platform Majority of code was written in C++ so that we can use that on different platforms
- Azure blob storage for storing the configuration files related to application.

2. ABC Kids Games for Toddlers

Organization: Greysprings; Platform: Android/iOS/Windows platform

Link: https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.greysprings.fun.learning.games.kids.abc

Roles and Responsibilities:

- Participate in sprint planning daily standup and sprint review
- Willingness to learn new technologies mostly open-source.
- Responsible for features development and handling iOS platform specific modules like inapp purchases, ad framework integration and release.

Tech stack used:

- cocos2d-x game engine, C++, cross platform development
- Specific Android, Windows and iOS platform projects for native support and development of platform specific features like in-app purchases and ads integration.
- Azure blob storage for storing the configuration files related to application.

3. School Learning games for Kids

Organization: Greysprings; **Platform:** Android/iOS/Windows platform

Link: https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.greysprings.kindergarten8

Roles and Responsibilities:

- Participate in sprint planning daily standup and sprint review
- Willingness to learn new technologies mostly open-source.
- Responsible for features development and handling iOS platform specific modules like inapp purchases, ad framework integration and release.

Tech stack used:

- cocos2d-x game engine, C++, cross platform development
- Specific Android, Windows and iOS platform projects for native support and development of platform specific features like in-app purchases and ads integration.
- Azure blob storage for storing the configuration files related to application.

4. Umbli – Preschools Management

Organization: Greysprings; Platform: Android/iOS

Roles and Responsibilities:

- Decision of the technologies and open-source products to be used in the development.
- Coordinate with development, testing and deployment teams.

- Responsible for development and maintenance of modules and features
- To hold and participate in product design and code review meetings.
- To participate in product design and code review meetings.
- Basic scripting and automation knowledge (python)
- Work collaboratively in a team environment and as an individual

Tech stack used:

- Android, swift(iOS) for frontend development, AWS S3 for storage and Parse Server as backend infrastructure

5. Fitnessmana

Organization: Fitnessmana; Platforms: Android

Link: https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.fm.fitnessmana

Roles and Responsibilities:

- Decision of the technologies and open-source products to be used in the development.
- Coordinate with development, testing and deployment teams.
- Continuously review the product and code for bugs, optimizations and performance improvements.
- Majorly worked on the android frontend, though have a basic understanding of backend infrastructure used.

Tech stack used:

 Android, AWS (DynamoDB, S3 storage, SQS, SNS, CloudWatch and EC2, Kubernetes and docker), MongoDB

Scaler Profile QR Code: